Guide to the Thomas Moore papers, 1804-1847 MS 015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Numbered copies, 251948 (Box 2)
  - T.M. to James Power, 1818 August 14; [557]; 251999; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1818 August 28; [559]; 251998; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1818 October 31; [566]; 251997; ALS
  - T.M. to William Linley, 1819 April 8; [574]; 251996; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Morgan, 1820 March 17; [587]; 251995; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, 1821 October; [611]; 251994; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, 1821 November 6; [613]; 251993; ALS
  - T.M. to John Murray, 1821 December 21; [615]; 251992; ALS
  - T.M. to John Hunt, 1822 December 24; [623]; 251991; ALS
  - T.M. to John Wilson Croker, 1823 March 23; [634]; 251990; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, 1823 April; [636]; 251989; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1823 June 30; [638]; 251988; ALS
  - T.M. to Frederick Byng, 1823 December 17; [642]; 251987; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1824 February 20; [645]; 251986; ALS
  - T.M. to Washington Irving, 1824 August; [653]; 251985; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Holland, 1825 April or May; [667]; 251984; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Holland, 1825 May 7; [668]; 251983; ALS
  - T.M. to Sir Walter Scott, 1825 July 24; [671]; 251982; ALS
  - T.M. to Charles Brinsley Sheridan, 1826 January 14; [687]; 251981; ALS
  - T.M. to Charles Brinsley Sheridan, 1826 April 16; [697]; 251980; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Owen Rees, 1827 February 14; [714]; 251979; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Billing, 1827 September 18; [735]; 251978; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Fellows, 1828 January 27; [757]; 251977; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Musters, 1828 January 29; [758]; 251976; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Higginson, 1828 February 3; [762]; 251975; ALS
  - T.M. to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1828 February 27; [763]; 251974; ALS
  - T.M. to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1828 March 19; [773]; 251973; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord John Russell, 1828 March 27; [775]; 251972; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Corsham, 1829 February 24; [807]; 251971; ALS
  - T.M. to Sir Thomas Lawrence, 1829 September 29; [863]; 251970; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Dudley, 1830 May 10; [928]; 251969; ALS
  - T.M. to Arthur O'Connor, 1831 March 10; [957]; 251968; ALS
  - T.M. to Arthur O'Connor, 1831 March 24; [958]; 251967; ALS
  - T.M. to Arthur O'Connor, 1831 April 15; [960]; 251966; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Brougham, 1831 July 19; [971]; 251965; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Brougham, 1831 July 20; [972]; 251964; ALS
  - T.M. to Captain Marryat, 1832 June 6; [1002]; 251963; ALS
  - T.M. to Louis McLane, 1832 June 13; [1004]; 251962; ALS
  - T.M. to James Corry, 1832 August 21; [1013]; 251961; ALS
  - T.M. to Dr. Dionysius Lardner, 1833 September 1; [1038]; 251960; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Elby, 1836 January 2; [1083]; 251959; ALS
  - T.M. to J.W. Wright, 1836 October 18; [1094]; 251958; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1838 May 10; [1143]; 251957; ALS
  - T.M. to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1840 December 1; [1199]; 251956; ALS
  - T.M. to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1841 January 2; [1200]; 251955; ALS
  - T.M. to Benjamin Robert Haydon, 1841 January; [1202]; 251954; ALS
  - T.M. to Edward Moxon, 1845 October 12; [1242]; 251953; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; [1273]; 251952; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; [1285]; 251951; ALS
  - T.M. to the Editor, Illustrated London News, [1287]; 251950; ALS
  - T.M. to Patrick B. Fitzpatrick, n.d.; [1294]; 251949; ALS
- Series IV: Unnumbered copies, 251915 (Box 2)
  - Addressee Unknown, 1800 October 28; 251947; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to James Power, [1813 May 11]; 251946; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1813]; 251945; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1829 April 6; 251944; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1830 October 4; 251943; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1830 October 5; 251942; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Bentley, 1847 June 5; 251941; ALS
  - T.M. to John Cooper, n.d.; 251940; ALS
  - T.M. to Lavinia Forster, n.d.; 251939; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 251938; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 251937; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 251936; ALS
  - J.W. Croker to Thomas Moore, 1811 October 26; 251935; (2 letters)
  - J.W. Croker to Thomas Moore, 1812 March, April; 251934
  - J.W. Croker to Thomas Moore, 1813 November 13; 251933
  - George Crabbe [to Thomas Moore], 1818 January 3; 251932
  - B.R. Haydon to Thomas Moore, 1828 February 26; 251931
  - B.R. Haydon to Thomas Moore, 1830 January 23; 251930
  - J.W. Croker Correspondence, 1811 April; 251929
  - J.W. Croker Correspondence, 1814 August; 251928
  - J.W. Croker Correspondence, 1817 October; 251927
  - J.W. Croker Correspondence, 1819 January; 251926
  - T. Crofton Croker to Robert Balmanno, 1849 May 4; 251925
  - T. Crofton Croker to Robert Balmanno, 1851 November 7; 251924
  - T. Crofton Croker to Robert Balmanno, 1853 July 29; 251923
  - T. Crofton Croker to Robert Balmanno, 1854 January 6; 251922
  - T. Crofton Croker to Robert Balmanno, 1854 January 11; 251921
  - Correspondence - J.W. Croker and Lord John Russell on some passages of Moore's Diary, 1854; 251920
  - Sale of Moore's Letters to Power, n.d.; 251919
  - Correspondence concerning purchase of Moore material, 1958 April 19 - 1972 August 22; 251918
  - Excerpts from catalogues advertising Moore material, n.d.; 251917
  - Commonplace Book [in Moore's handwriting] in black notebook, 251916
- Series V: Addenda to Thomas Moore Letters, (1976-1978); 251890
  Scope and Contents note
  This collection is a continuation of Woodson Research Library's earlier collection of the Letters of Thomas Moore (MS 015). The letters collected were purchased from Winifred A. Meyers (Autographs), Ltd. and Kenneth W. Rendell, Inc. Also included are four engravings of the poet, purchased from Colburn and Tegg (Hollis, New York.). These purchases were made between 1976 and 1978.
  - Thomas Moore to Mr. Power, n.d. (after 1807); 251914; ALS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Henry Lee, 18(14) Feb. 7; 251913; ALS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to John Benet, 183(5) Apr. 7; 251912; ALS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Mrs. Twirlie, 1837 Jan. 31; 251911; ALS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Philip Crumpe, 1839 Feb. 15; 251910; ALS (Box 2)
  - (Thomas Moore) to Mrs. Murray, 1841 May 1; 251909; Envelope (Box 2)
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d. (1841 May 1?); 251908; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to John Bullock, 1845 Aug. 25; 251907; ANS (Box 2)
  - Four engravings of Thomas Moore, 251906 (Box 2)
  - Several Addressees, 1825-27; 251905; ALS (Box 2)
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 251904; ALS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to son Russell, 251903; AL(inc.) (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Revd. E. Goddard, 1837, Sept. 26; 251902; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Dr. Ainslie, 251901; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to George F. Mulvany, 1833 Feb. 7; 251900; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to George F. Mulvany, 1833 Feb. 8; 251899; ANS (Box 2)
  - George F. Mulvany to J. P. Vereker, 1886 Aug. 2; 251898; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to James Corry, 1845 July 4th; 251897; ANS (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to James Corry [on his making me a present of a Wine-strainer], n.d.; 251896; ANS (Box 2)
  - T.M. to Charles Parnell, 1832 Jan. 2; 251895; ALS (Box 2)
  - Fragments, n.d., 251894 (Box 2)
  - Fragments - pages from journal, 251893 (Box 2)
  - Photocopies from Lives of the Lords Strangford and letters to Byron, 251892 (Box 2)
  - Photostat copies, 1818-1846; 251891 (Box 3)
- Series VI: Thomas Moore Letters on Microfilm, 251881
  Eight small boxes of microfilm are included in the collection:
  - Letters and Notes Held at Pierpont Morgan Library, 1802-1843; 251889 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 1)
    16 autographed letters and/or notes for the period 1802-1843. Recipients include J. Taylor, James Carpenter, James Power, Samuel Rogers. Several of the addressees are unknown. Also included is an undated check. Originals of thes microfilm are in the Pierpont Morgan Library. Items on the microfilm are not to be reproduced or quoted without the express permission of the Trustees of the Pierpont Morgan Library.
  - Manuscripts and Music Held at the National Library of Ireland, 1802-1852; 251888 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 2)
    ALS, Ms, ANS, AL, DS, and music. About 70 items in all, covering the period 1802-1852. Among the adressees are James Perry, the Morning Chronicle, Robert Montgomery, T. S. Rice, D. F. Ryan, Edward R. Moran, Richard Bentley. Also included are Thomas Moore's will, and the Certificate of Administration of Thomas Moore's will (originals in the Bristol District Registry). Originals are housed in the National Library of Ireland. Items may not be reproduced without the permission of the National Library of Ireland.
  - Letters and Notes Held at the Huntington Library, 1810-1845; 251887 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 3)
    27 autographed letters and notes written by Moore between 1810 and 1845. Among the addressees (most of whom are unknown) are James Power, James Carpenter and William L. Bowles. Included on the microfilm are 2 pages from Moore's "Life of Sir Edward Fitzgerald" (typescript). Originals are located in the Huntington Library and Art Gallery. Written permission to quote from, to reproduce, or to reprint must be obtained from copyright owners (if material is copyrighted) or from the Director of the Huntington Library.
  - Letters Held at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1812-1844; 251886 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 4)
    14 autographed letters between 1812 and 1844. Addressees include James Power, James Carpenter and Washington Irving. An inventory of the film's contents and a restriction statement precedes the letters. Originals owned by the Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
  - Letters, Notes, and Manuscripts Held at the Harvard College Library, 1813-1844; 251885 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 5)
    27 autographed letters, notes and manuscripts written by Moore between 1813 and 1844. Addressees include James Carpenter, James Power, William Bowles, Richard Bentley, Edward Moxon and others. Microfilm made by the Harvard College Library. No restriction statement on film.
  - Letters Held at the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1815-1829; 251884 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 6)
    Letters written between 1815-1829. Addressees include Mr. James Power. Originals located in the Historical Society of Pennsylvania; and the right to reproduce the material must be secured from the Director of the Society, applied for and granted in writing. A partial inventory precedes the film.
  - Letters Held at the Huntington Library, 1815-1843; 251883 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 7)
    7 ALS dated 1815-1843. Addressees are Mr. Longman, Mrs. Belcher; other unknown; certain letters pertain to musical matters. Originals are located in the Huntington Library and Art Gallery. Written permission to quote from, to reproduce, or to reprint material must be obtained from the copyright owner (copyrighted material) or from the Director of the Huntington Library. A partial inventory and restriction statement precedes the film.
  - Letters Held at Trinity College Library, ca. 1830; 251882 (Box 2, Item Microfilm Box 8)
    4 ALS written around 1830 by Moore. Three of the letters are in the Trinity College Library; the other is the property of Lieutenant-Col. M. O'C. Fitzsimmon of Glencullen Co., Dublin. There is no inventory or restriction statement on the microfilm.
- Series VII: Addenda to Thomas Moore Letters (Oversize), 251850; 0.637 GB Gigabytes (DVD containing 0.637 GB, 10 tiff files, 600ppi) (Box 4)
  (Sm. Ms. box) Corrected galleys of poems, including the following titles, and digitized copy on DVD:
  - Speech on the Umbrella Question, 251880
  - A Pastoral Ballad, 251879
  - A Late Scene at Swanage, 251878
  - Wo! Wo!, 251877
  - The Living Dog and the Dead Lion, 251876
  - Ode to Don Miguel, 251875
  - Ode to the Goddess Ceres, 251874
  - A Hymn of Welcome After the Recess, 251873
  - Memorabilia of Last Week, 251872
  - All in the Family Way, a new pastoral ballad, 251871
  - Ballad for the Cambridge Election, 251870
  - The Millennium, 251869
  - The Three Doctors, 251868
  - Mr. Rodger Dodsworth, 251867
  - Copy of an Intercepted Despatch, 251866
  - Cotton and Corn, 251865
  - The Canonization of Saint B-tt-rw-rth, 251864
  - An Incantation, sung by the bubble spirit, 251863
  - A Dream of Turtle, 251862
  - The Donky and his Panniers, 251861
  - Ode to the Sublime Porte, 251860
  - Corn and Catholics, 251859
  - A Case of Libel, 251858
  - The Slave, 251857
  - Ode to Ferdinand, 251856
  - Hat versus Wig, 251855
  - The Periwinkles and the Locusts, 251854
  - Tout Pour La Tripe, 251853
  - Enigma, 251852
  - Dog-day Reflections, 251851